All of you want chocolate ? I 'll see what I can do .
Roberto ! Excuse me .
Happy Thanksgiving . All the best . Happy Thanksgiving . God bless you .
Happy Thanksgiving . All the very best .
Bless you .
Happy Thanksgiving .
Get the police .
Get on the radio .
Coming through !
BP 's 80 / 40 . He 's already had a liter of D5W .
Happy Thanksgiving , guys . Get the priest into C , now .
- Who 's the perp ? - Benjamin Mears , age 37 . New York license .
- Hold him in A. - A , as in abused by a priest ?
It hurt a bit ?
Well , that 's nothing compared to the fires you 'll face on Judgment Day .
Now , let 's see what we have here .
Hey , buddy . Wake up .
Yeah , that 's it .
Now give me one good reason why
as a good Christian , I shouldn 't let you die right here .
Jerusalem 's Lot .
No one pronounced Jerusalem 's Lot dead on the morning of February 6th .
No one knew it was .
By and large , the town , not knowing it was dead
would go off to their jobs with no inkling
of what lay ahead .
Looking at Jerusalem 's Lot
is like peering through a pane of ice at your childhood .
it 's wavy and misty , but most of it 's the same .
McDougall !
Lawrence Crockett is the richest man in Salem 's Lot , but the irs will never know .
Like his neighbors , he relies on the community to keep his secrets .
The social pact is the foundation of every small town .
Macy , tell Richard Straker I 'll be 1 0 minutes late .
Oh , a Mr. Mears stopped by .
- l told him you 'd be out at the trailer park . - Mears ?
Balls . The writer . You told him I was here ?
i 'm sorry , Larry . You have to tell me when you 're hiding .
Larry ?
Ben Mears . Can I interest you in a mobile home ?
Great little place to raise a family .
I 'll just take the keys to the house , thanks .
- Still living in New York City ? - Yeah .
I was , till I sublet my place .
I saw the Marsten house from the road. lt 's empty , right ?
No , I sold it. I 'm sorry .
Finally did . Same people who bought the Laundromat .
I have an agreement to rent that . I have the paperwork in my car .
So sue me. I 'm sorry .
Look , Eva Prunier runs a clean boarding house on Clift Street .
Who would buy that house ?
- Two gentlemen , antique dealers . - And they 're aware of its story ?
- l suppose . How could they not be ? - But you didn 't tell them .
- l don 't remember . - But you remember our agreement .
What do you want me to say , Mr. Mears ? The deal is done .
Would you mind moving your car ?
Go on , Mears . You wanna be a Bloody Pirate , don 't you ?
Come on , Mears . We 've all been inside .
You a wuss or a Pirate ?
The town has secrets , but sees through lies
even the ones you tell yourself .
What are you doing coming back to the place where you lived as a boy ?
Trying to recapture something that was irrevocably lost ?
What magic do you expect to recapture by walking roads you once walked ?
They 're now probably asphalted
and straightened
and litter-shot with tourist beer cans .
Do you even know ?
The kids who ride Charlie Rhodes' school bus are the best-behaved in town .
in the entire school district , for that matter . Charlie Rhodes is a bitter vet
who runs his bus the same way he ran Kilo Company in Da Nang .
Living proof that time does not heal all wounds .
You got a lot to talk about ?
Take it outside .
Don 't romanticize the town because it 's small .
Or because you fished its waters for pickerel and steelies as a boy .
This town knows darkness .
You can 't find them , grind them .
Who said that ?
Champ .
The town knows darkness
and the poor kids , like Mark Petrie
know more than their village peers about the darkness of the human soul .
Surprise , surprise .
Salem 's Lot is an accumulation of three parts .
Ass-wipe !
The sum of which are greater than their whole .
What the hell are you two making all those signs for ?
He got my hat . He won 't give it back .
The town is the people , the buildings they 've erected to den or do business in .
There you go . Problem solved .
And it is the land .
Screw Charlie Rhodes . I 'd walk every day
if my mother wasn 't tweaked about the " preverts . "
You meet a lot of preverts , Ralphie ?
More than I know . Look at Charlie
a normal jagoff , till you look under the visor of his bus .
- Shut up . - l know kids who 've seen them .
- Seen what ? - Pictures . Porn .
Dude , we gotta check this , all right ?
We 'll hook up tonight , see how Charlie gets his rocks off .
Hey , Petrie ... .
The people are Scotch , English and French .
There are others , of course
a smattering , like a fistful of pepper thrown in a bucket of salt .
Matt Burke teaches English at the high school
and is a life-long bachelor .
- Morning , Matt . - Morning .
Matt 's alternative life in Portland is tolerated
so long as he keeps it out of the classroom .
The buildings here are nearly all constructed of honest wood .
And when i was a boy , it was largely agreed that Hubie Marsten
built the finest home in Jerusalem 's Lot
before going soft in the attic .
Mr. Mears ?
Mr. Mears , I 'm Susan Norton .
We traded e-mails a few years back . You probably don 't remember .
I went to Boston University and couldn 't decide between art and English .
- Please , sit . - lf l 'm not bothering you .
Not at all .
- So what 'd you choose ? - Art .
Nothing against writing .
Everyone knows you grew up here . I found it inspiring .
- Oh , thank you . - l lived in New York for a year after school .
But I couldn 't paint the rent . So I 'm home reevaluating .
New York 's for artists with generous parents .
And the Lot is for hobbyists who paint lighthouses and lobster boats .
I wish you 'd been more persistent with your e-mails , Susan .
Because I 'm interesting or blonde ?
Because you 're an interesting blonde .
- What brings you back ? - Work .
A new book . Boring People in the Perfect Town ?
It surrounds the Marsten house , but I 'm not telling anyone .
A haunted house . Not your genre .
Complex characters can elevate genre .
Hubie Marsten , a respected pillar of the community until the moment
he blew his wife away and hung himself from a rafter .
Small-town Shakespeare .
You are the one who found them .
Yes .
- l tried to rent the place . - You actually wanted to live there ?
Yeah , it 's my
attraction-repulsion compulsion .
Kinky things went on in that place in Hubie 's day .
I heard .
- You met the owners ? - Two guys. I hope they 're gay .
It might alleviate some of the gossip off me .
Can I get you something ?
Hello. I 'm Susan 's mother .
It 's good to meet both of you .
Susan Norton , Norton 's Cafe .
I 'm slinging latte here till I can move back to New York .
I think that building you mentioned might be a metaphor for something bigger in your life .
Does it always have to be something bigger ?
Like a theme ?
There would be if it were my book .
The land is granite-bodied .
Farming it is a thankless , miserable business .
You sure you wanna live out here , Dud ? It 's getting cold .
I got a stove in the shack , Mike . I 'm all right .
We need the leaves and tree cutting for fill .
- Don 't burn them . - l won 't burn them , Mike .
- What you got there ? - He must have got thirsty .
- Hey , put that down . - lt 's for my girlfriend .
You got a girlfriend now ? Who ?
Let 's go , gimp !
- Who ? - l can 't say !
Okay , Floyd !
You better toss it away anyway . She 'll think you 're a freak !
The Rogers family ran a dairy here for generations till Dud was born .
it was sold to the town , which built the hospital Dud needs
but can 't visit without insurance .
- Royce , could you excuse us , please ? - Why ?
This is what Sandy McDougall gave up high school for .
Your son has a significant contusion .
I wanna talk to Sandy about it
alone .
A winter malaise is epidemic in small towns .
Dr. James Cody fights it with fine dining and new clothes .
Others self-medicate with alcohol and television .
Little Roy hasn 't had breakfast .
What happened , Sandy ?
I turned my back for a second , and he fell off the changing table .
It 's the truth .
Sandy , how long have you been married , now ?
Six months .
Still live in Crockett 's trailer park ?
Not having money doesn 't make us bad parents .
No , of course not .
Sandy , I 'm required by law to report this type of injury .
- lt 's not what you think , Jimmy . - lt 's not ?
Sandy , was it Royce ?
Look , this marriage isn 't all I thought , but little Roy 's okay .
We had some fun times didn 't we ?
Dancing ? New Year 's at Dell 's ?
Please , don 't report it . Give us a chance .
Bring the baby back tomorrow .
You 're a good man , Jimmy .
And a good doctor .
If I 'd been a little smarter
or drunker that New Year 's
who knows ?
You stay because a small town knows you
and thereby owns you . Sure as the bank , the car dealer and the Sears in Livingston .
The kitchen is available to all guests from 5 a.m. to 9 p.m.
Fresh sheets are provided weekly
and rents are negotiable for those who wanna work .
Do you have a room with a view ?
Oh , yes , I do .
Would you believe it 's my hardest room to rent ?
Ed , a moment please . Mr. Mears will be staying with us .
- For a few weeks . - Pleasure .
Most tourists leave soon as their tank 's full .
I grew up in the Lot as a child with my Aunt Cynthia . Cynthia Stowens .
I knew Cynthia .
- You 're her nephew ? - That 's right .
- The boy who was in the Marsten house ? - l am .
You 're the one who found Hubie and his wife , Birdie ?
Goddamn . You were a ballsy little fella .
Please , come and look .
Some of the men are building me a rec room .
Gentlemen , this is Ben Mears .
Mr. Mears used to live in the Lot .
I know Mr. Mears .
You ever write a book about Afghanistan ?
- l did . - Waste of paper , that was .
- Oh , Mr. Blair . - That 's okay. I 'm glad somebody read it .
Civilian casualties aren 't avoidable in combat. I was in the Corps ' 64 to ' 70 .
Tourists like yourself writing about war
are naive , dangerous , borderline traitorous .
- What do you think about war crimes ? - War crimes , my ass .
There 's three good Marines rotting in Leavenworth right now
because of Mr. Ben Mears .
Beneath the postcard camouflage , there 's little good in small towns .
Mostly boredom , interspersed with a dull , mindless , moronic evil .
I love them .
I just love these brick walls .
Lawrence , son
I called you over an hour ago .
My secretary screwed up .
Fire her . She makes you look bad .
Thanks .
The shop looks good , Mr. Straker .
Well , the truth be told , we don 't really need it .
Ninety-five percent of our business is done online .
Well , that explains opening in November .
Weather is regional . We are global .
Madam !
What a beautiful-looking letterbox .
My father made it by hand .
Well , your father is a fine craftsman .
I will give you
1 0 dollars to keep it .
You just turn around and take it back .
But if you insist , I will buy that box from you for
$ 60 , and I will find a good home for it .
I need the money .
Well , there you have it . Thank you very much . Do come back again .
There 's another chore I need you to do for me , Lawrence .
You 'll need a large truck . Be at the Portland docks tonight , 7 : 00 sharp .
- Okay . - There are a dozen crates to be picked up .
All save one are to be brought here to the shop .
The largest contains an extremely valuable sideboard
a Hepplewhite .
That is to be taken to my house .
The movers will recognize it by its size .
Yes , sir .
They can leave it in the foyer . The front door will be open .
Got it .
When do we meet your partner , Mr. Barlow ?
In his own good time .
This is fancy. ls it valuable ?
It 's an 1 8th-century harmony pin .
Belonged to a whoremaster 's mistress .
Take it , Lawrence .
Take it
for services rendered .
Back it up there , Floyd .
Yeah .
What are you doing ?
Give it here .
Give me that .
Get off my property .
He didn 't mean anything by it .
I know what he meant . Get him out of here .
Larry , Dud 's harmless .
i 'll put him on another route . He 's like a brother .
What if I find another trash service and landscaper , huh ?
- How about I pull all my accounts , Mike ? - Don 't say that .
- l 'm more than saying . - Maybe you should talk to your daughter .
One more crack like that and you 're both through . Finito . Do you understand ?
- ls that yours ? - l threw it out. lt 's too small .
- You can 't encourage that retard . - Like I would . He 's disgusting .
I 've got 1 2 crates arriving at the Portland docks tonight I need picked up .
Antiques .
- Stay out of there . - l need money .
- Do you wanna make some money or not ? - Look , I 'll help with the crates .
- Call me later . - Finders keepers .
How does it look , Daddy ? is it too trashy ?
- What ? - Nothing. I was just thinking .
So , what were you saying about expression ?
Graffiti is a condemnation of architecture .
Kids create on top of buildings because they don 't see the expression within .
What is the expression of a building ?
Its soul , its ambiance , a byproduct of design .
Or events within .
Back to the Marsten house ?
Sorry .
We can talk about your work .
We can talk about the dog .
I 'm glad you called .
Get off the stage , boy .
Ben , found an old friend of yours .
- Ben Mears , welcome back . - Hey .
- Hello , Susan . - Mr . Burke .
I don 't expect you remember your 8th-grade teacher .
Oh , no , I do . He was the tough guy who taught for three reasons .
June , July and August . Right . I was being facetious , Ben .
I teach high-school English now .
Can you find time to share your success with my class ?
It 's more of a working vacation .
- You sure ? - Yeah .
I 'm disappointed .
We can talk all night . The kids want celebrities .
When was the last time you saw a kid read a book ?
All I see are headphones and cell phones .
You 're right , Weasel . Literature 's become elitist .
It 's like black-and-white photography .
You know , Ben , I half expected that cynicism from you .
- lt 's there between the lines . - l like Ben 's work .
- Come on , we 're just drinking here . - lt 's okay .
Are you one of the few in town who read the book ?
Or did you just skim the reviews ?
I read Damage Control and Marching in Heels .
Well , don 't hold back .
The world acknowledges your talent as a writer .
I might argue your work is antagonistic when it needn 't be
emotionally detached and lacking a moral center .
If that 's the way you speak with your English class
I would be honored to visit .
Champ !
Come on , boy !
I 'll be lookout .
Panties a little tight ?
All right .
- He 's coming . - Get out . Get out . Get out . Go . Go . Go .
- Catch you tomorrow . - All right .
Champ !
What 'd you see ?
Dead soldiers . Their eyes are poked out . Their ears are missing .
A soldier feeding pizza to a lady 's head !
You 're a douche bag , Ralphie .
Wait !
- Where are we ? - lt looks like- -
Mark ?
It has to be Mark .
Wait. I can 't breathe .
Danny !
No , no !
Danny ! Danny !
No !
I think Susie wants out .
She 's always e-mailing other guys , old teachers , old boyfriends .
Well , how do you know ?
I set up a computer for her and her mother .
- So of course I got the passwords . - Floyd .
Floyd .
- You set up my computer . - Relax. I don 't know your business .
I don 't want to . What ? You have nothing to worry about .
- Nothing 's wrong with surfing The Barnyard . - You son of a bitch !
Yeah , I bet you felt real sorry for that dog .
I can 't believe you !
You could get that .
- Hello . - Mrs . Petrie .
Hi , I 'm Marjorie Glick . We 've never met .
Look , are my boys still at your house ? If so , could you send them home , please ?
One second , Marjorie. lt 's Mrs. Glick . She thinks her boys are here .
- They went home . - Mark says they went home .
- They must be on the way . - Does he know what time they left ?
- l didn 't see anybody . - We were outside . They left at , like , 8 .
Mark says the boys left around 8 , Marjorie .
- Okay . Great. lt 's getting late . - it is .
- Would you like to speak with Mark ? - No .
No . No , I guess not . Thank you .
- We 'll have to meet some time . - That would be nice .
Not in this life .
- Danny ? - l found him lying in the road .
My God , is he all right ?
- Where 's Ralphie ? - Call an ambulance .
Hubie ?
Birdie ?
It 's Floyd .
Forgot to pay your electric .
Hey , you gonna give us a hand here , Hubie Jr . ?
Crockett 's paying us 1 00 bucks to deliver this crate .
If I said to you , Mike
I 'll pay you 200 bucks
to come into the Marsten house alone at night ...
- ... would you do it ? - Hell , no .
Me neither .
I find that humorous .
This place used to keep me up at night .
As a kid , I could see it from my bedroom window .
I wouldn 't be able to sleep unless my mother pulled the shade .
Where are you going ?
I wanna see Hubie 's bedroom .
And the bathroom where Birdie ... .
Straker ?
Let 's get out of here .
You better get back in there . Birdie needs a boyfriend .
- You heard footsteps . We both did , right ? - l heard squealing .
I think that was you .
Hey , Mike , what do these Beemers run ?
Hurry up .
I told you it was Straker .
Just spread out .
No sign of the Glick boy .
- -find evidence of the boy .
Mark , what were you boys doing on this side of town ?
We were just playing flashlight tag .
Charlie Rhodes lives just over the hill . Did you hear about his dog ?
Yeah , I heard it died .
Mrs. Glick says you and her boys had some trouble with Charlie on the school bus .
You got him angry . Did you see Charlie last night ?
No .
Shut up , Cujo ! Quiet !
Hi .
Mr. Mears . Surprised to see you this morning .
A child won 't last long in this cold .
These Norton girls are angels , Ben . Before them it was Eva Prunier .
You may not see it , but our landlady was the prettiest in the county .
Eva 's still pretty. I can see it .
What I see in Eva , it 's magic .
Careful , Ed . Mr. Mears will turn your heartbreak into a bestseller .
Our secrets are safe .
Ben 's working on a piece of historical fiction .
Yeah , I heard .
- Marsten house ? - Who told you that ?
Little bird in the library .
What was it like in the house ? Tell us about when you found her .
You 'll have to wait for the book .
Come on . Give us a preview .
I was 9 years old , living out on Burns Road with my aunt , Cynthia .
I went in on a dare from the Bloody Pirates .
Was Hubie already hanging , or did you see him do it ?
I saw .
I spent the whole night in there until a friend finally got my Aunt Cynthia .
Terrible place , looking down on this town like a dark idol .
- There 's a quote for the liner jacket . - We need some more water .
Yeah , I 'll help .
What about Ronnie Barnes ?
Did you see him too ?
No .
No , I never did .
I 'm so embarrassed .
I know you didn 't want people to know what you 're writing .
I went to the library. I mentioned your name to Loretta Starcher .
Now the whole town knows . I was trying to help .
- lt 's okay . - l was researching the Marsten 's for you .
I wanted it to be a nice surprise .
- Are you mad ? I would be . - Ben Mears .
Didn 't mean to interrupt . May I speak with you ?
I 'll call you .
I know you 're on to something with this book .
- Never thought we 'd see you again . - lt 's nice to see you too , chief .
So give me an alibi .
I was having drinks with Susan till 9 .
Matt Burke says you left Dell 's at 8 because you wanted to work .
It might have been 8 .
Did you see any children on your drive ?
- Any flashlights in the woods ? - No .
Anything unusual ? Maybe a van parked alongside the road ?
No .
All right. I do appreciate your help today .
That dog in the cemetery , who found it first ?
I did .
Okay .
Floyd , everything work out last night ?
He paid me , Larry . Thanks for the job .
Pocket money . Keep your lady happy .
Well , what can I do you for ?
You heard about the missing kid ?
A parent 's worst fear .
Well , while we were up at the Marsten house making that delivery
I looked in the back of the new owner 's car .
I saw a plastic bag in the back seat .
It was leaking .
Was it little-boy-sized ?
It was head-sized .
The new owner is Richard Straker .
You think he killed the missing Glick boy and kept the head ?
I 'm not saying all that .
What will that do to his antique business ?
- lt was leaking all over the leather seats . - Did you tell Mike what you saw ?
No. I didn 't think much of it at the time , until today .
So why tell me ? Go tell Parkins Gillespie , if you think it 's important .
I 'm telling you because you know him .
Relax , Floyd .
Straker called me this morning , excited about tackle and shacks .
Seems he tried his hand at ice fishing and finds it relaxing .
Ice fishing .
Maybe he bagged a tuna or cod , whatever you swamp Yankees pull out of these lakes .
Well , that 's a relief .
I was driving myself crazy .
I understand
but we have to be careful , Floyd .
Loose talk can ruin people .
My first suspect was the other new guy in town . Some hotshot writer .
- What writer ? - Mears .
Nice enough , but a city guy . A bit abrasive . You know him ?
Ben Mears .
I know of him .
I better get back to work .
Hey , thanks for last night .
And thanks for coming to me first on this .
Bishop 's Lake .
That 's the best spot for ice fishing .
I 'll tell Straker .
You 're on my short list , buddy .
Dud .
I 'm sorry , Dud . I can 't use you today .
What ? Why not ?
Ruth Crockett . You shouldn 't have been messing with her , Dud .
Now Larry 's threatened to pull all the accounts .
Well , I can 't put you on the truck , Dud . I can 't afford it .
But we 're friends , Mike . We 're best friends .
I know. I know .
We still are .
What will I do ?
I don 't know .
You know , I 'll help you find another job .
Until then , look , just take this
to hold you over , all right .
It 's not your fault , Dud .
Whatever you did , it was just , you know , misunderstood .
I 'm sorry .
Danny , can you hear me ?
Danny ? Can you hear me ?
If you can hear me , blink your eyes .
He 's in acute mental shock .
Maybe from excessive fear , grief
or some sort of emotional trauma .
Excuse me .
He 's getting worse .
Marjorie .
I believe this is Danny 's .
- Yes , doctor . - Doctor .
Sometimes the power of prayer and local facilities have limits .
It 's shock , Father . Your car didn 't hit him .
He 'll snap out of it .
Stop it .
Hi . How 's little Roy today ?
He 's fine , Jimmy . See for yourself .
Hello . Hi . How you doing ?
I really appreciate your help , Jimmy .
Maybe after you finish with Roy , I could buy you lunch .
You know , I usually have my lunch in the cafeteria , Sandy .
Well , little Roy and I could join you .
That wouldn 't be a good idea .
- What would your husband say ? - " Order a salad . Your ass is fat . "
That was a joke .
Most doctors love kids . They have pictures all over the office .
It helps the patient relax .
They figure , " This doctor 's so busy thinking about his kids
he 's not thinking about my naked body . "
Yeah , well , I love kids , you know . They 're great to work with .
They have this , you know
way to thank you with their eyes .
Yeah , but you love your toys too . I mean , look at this car .
- Still a player . - Player ?
- You think this car 's too dope for Doctor C. ? - Maybe .
I only said " player " because I know how you were at Dell 's .
- l danced with you , remember ? - Oh , yeah. I remember .
Would you pull over ? I have to check on little Roy .
Sure .
I can 't .
You 're still a nice guy .
You are .
If I could have chose everything in my life
I 'd have chose a man like you .
The more interesting items are in the store .
I 'm sorry. I was looking for a local boy who 's missing .
I don 't think you 'll find him here .
No .
I 'm Ben Mears , Mr. Straker . Been anxious to meet you .
Richard .
You and your partner took the house I was interested in .
You comfortable up there ?
Well , it 's a handful , Ben .
I hope you find the little boy .
Somehow , I don 't think we will . Not alive , anyway .
How 's your alibi ?
Excuse me ?
The police spoke with me today . We 're both new in town .
We 're not even new. ln a small town like this , we 're strangers the first 20 years .
Well , I happen to like it here , Ben .
And your partner ?
- Mr . Barlow ? - You a reporter ?
Writer .
- Critics call me " typist . " - " Typist " ?
Typist .
Well , if you 're curious about the house ...
The truth is the place scares me .
Well , then you never intended to take it , did you , Mr. Typist ?
- lt 's Romeo . - More like Hannibal .
Ruth !
- Can I talk to you ? - Send him for pizza .
- Hey , go wash my car ! - Shut up .
I got fired , Ruth .
Mike said I shouldn 't have been messing with you .
I was thinking maybe you could talk to your father so I can get my job back .
It wouldn 't do any good . He 's mega-protective .
- l hate my father more than you do . - Really ?
Well , I still like you , Ruth . I really do .
You seem like a nice person , Dud .
But that stuff at my house was just to make my father mad .
- But , Ruth- - - l 'm sorry , Dud , but you gotta get real .
Get out of here , gimp !
You 're not my best friend , Mike .
Not anymore .
Dump 's closed , mister .
I 'm just watching the fires .
It scares the animals away .
Just the rats .
Smokes them from their holes .
Yeah . Where will they go ?
I guess they 'll find another hole .
You from around here ?
Yeah , just over the hill .
- What are you writing there ? - Nothing .
I lost my job .
Mike was my best friend since junior high .
It 's his backhoe .
- l 'll wash it off . - No , leave it .
I didn 't do anything wrong .
I was just talking with Ruth Crockett , my girlfriend
and her father got crazy
and told Mike he had to fire me or he 'd lose all his work .
Yeah , that 's too bad .
Say , aren 't you one of the fellas that bought the Marsten place ?
- Very good . - Are there any ghosts in that old house ?
Ghosts ?
No .
- No ghosts . - l didn 't think so .
Well , anyway
it 's always nice when someone comes down to , you know , shoot the breeze
but the dump closes at 6 and it 's half past 9 now , so ... .
Dud
I noticed your limping .
Curvature of the spine ?
- Does that bother you ? - Nope .
I can work fine .
I meant in other ways .
No .
Well
girls .
Just girls .
Their boyfriends , the other kids ?
Sometimes they laugh .
What were you to say if I gave you a chance
to be equal to those boys and girls ?
Or maybe even a little more . Would you take it ?
Equal ?
Danny .
Danny ?
Come on , Danny , it 's me
your brother , Ralphie .
Remember ?
You left me in the woods .
Ralphie ?
- l 'm just messing with you , Danny . - Go away .
Danny , I 'm not mad .
Danny .
I knew you were scared .
Cripes , I was scared too .
But not anymore .
Danny
I 'm messing with you , Danny .
I ain 't scared at all .
Let me in , Danny .
Don 't let Mom and Dad blame you .
All right .
You went to lunch with Sandy McDougall ?
- What 's wrong with that ? - Oh , nothing .
She 's 1 9 , married , barely educated . What else is right ?
What 's going on here ?
Now , who remembers the Morris chair ?
This .
Such an excellent example .
Very popular in Berkeley .
Look at that leather .
Please be kind enough to tell your friends we 're open
and that our prices are so very reasonable .
Madam
this drop-leaf table would look beautiful in a foyer
or in a servants ' entrance .
I am the only servant in my house .
And I am Richard Straker .
Eva Prunier. I own a boarding house on Clift Street .
Eva Prunier .
Your name is familiar .
And your accent .
Excuse me ?
Tell me , Eva
of all the old parlor games , which one do you miss the most ?
As you may share a little morphine avec his little friend .
I am jealous .
You must have been so young at that time then .
All you little village girls , what , 1 6 years old ? Fifteen ?
Did you give to Hubie
what I think you gave to him ?
Oh , I knew it .
- And did you wear his goat 's-head mask ? - Stop it !
I taught Ben Mears in the eighth grade . He survived .
Since then , he 's had a distinguished literary career .
In 2001 , he was captured by Taliban troops
while reporting the Afghan war .
He was rescued from certain death by U.S. Marines .
On the return trek
Ben 's Marines killed 1 0 Afghan villagers .
Damage Control is a factual account of the incident .
Three Marines were court-martialed and imprisoned .
Ben received the Pulitzer Prize . Mr. Mears is in town researching his new book
on the Marsten house .
Mr. Mears , should anyone in their right mind trust an author ?
A good author illuminates truth .
- Yes . - What 's the truth about this town ?
I used to think nothing happened here .
But the truth is everything happens here .
One has to look close in a small town .
The beauty is in the details .
You have all the horror of Qalai Janghi prison right here in one battered child .
All the beauty of Michelangelo in the alabaster calf of one
shoulder-high waitress .
The longing you feel for the boy or girl in the next row
is equal to or greater than what your favorite musician feels
for his favorite supermodel .
Never minimize your feelings .
Or this town .
What 's the truth about the Marines that saved you in Afghanistan ?
I 'm not a waitress or shoulder-high .
- Let me checked those Michelangelo calves . - lt was metaphors on the fly .
- What do you want from me ? - Proof .
And they really liked him ?
I 'll say they warmed up to him .
The boy went from mental shock to extreme anemia overnight .
What our grandfathers would call wasting away .
That poor family . Two sons .
Can you imagine ?
The red-cell count on a 1 4-year-old boy should run between 85 and 95 percent .
Danny 's was 45 .
- How long until people make a connection ? - Here it comes .
Come on . Ben , the whole town 's talking .
The house .
It 's like a curse .
Did you know that Hubie Marsten 's trucking firm in Boston was a front ?
Hubie was questioned twice by police . Once in Boston , and once in Malden .
The Malden thing was for the murder of an 1 1 - year-old boy .
Hubie and his wife moved to the Lot in 1 958 .
Between ' 58 and ' 74 , five children disappeared .
But we 've had no missing kids since Hubie died . Not one .
Now the house is occupied and we have one boy missing and another one dead .
So the house is a beacon for evil men .
It attracted you .
Ben , I 'm sure what you saw there as a boy still haunts you .
- You think ? - lt stayed in the town 's consciousness too .
Not just because tales of nastiness do , but I think because of location .
It looks down on us
like it 's judging us .
Or it 's the mirror by which you judge yourselves .
We have to go up there .
Introduce ourselves to the new squire ?
- On behalf of the town , of course . - l 've met the squire .
- lt 's research . - Susan , stay away from there .
Ben , you 're committed to the truth .
Why don 't you tell us why you 're really here ?
You 're not writing a book on the Marsten house . Right ?
No . No , I 'm not .
What do you mean ?
- Ben ? - The book is a non-fiction look
at the roots of domestic evil .
You 're writing about us ?
- Of course he is . - You lied ? To everyone ?
Haunted houses are not my genre .
So we 're evil . We 're a small town , small-minded and evil ?
- l won 't be a character in your stupid book . - Hey , Susan !
You will find evil if you want it , Ben .
Racism , greed , envy .
But we have heroes here too .
- l 'm sure . - lf you 're gonna look at this town
look fair and throw away your preconceptions .
I 've seen the good , and it far outweighs any bad .
We 're wrapping up for the night .
Eva ?
You all right ?
No , I don 't think so .
What is it , Eva ?
That house .
It haunts me .
I used to sneak up there with Eva Werts and Loretta Starcher .
We were young , bored .
Hubie and Birdie Marsten were alive .
I 'm ashamed of the things we did .
You were just a kid .
I used to write letters in French for Marsten , to a man in Marseilles .
Marsten admired this man , said he was beyond good and evil .
Horrifying , sublime .
I 'm thinking about the missing boy and his brother , Ed. l feel terrible .
I feel as though the invitations that I wrote
are somehow being answered .
- After 50 years ? - Well , suppose he had a partner or a son ?
No , no .
Eva
you know how I feel .
I liked your husband. I respected him .
But I love you now .
And these last 1 0 , 1 5 years of our lives
they can be great together .
This loving you from afar was killing me .
Mom ?
it 's Danny .
i found Ralphie .
Go away . Stop it .
Who is this ?
I wish you 'd told me earlier about the dog , Michael .
I 'd have postponed the funeral .
It was dead , Father . It was hanging on the fence .
Yes , but now all this land has got to be reconsecrated .
Technically speaking , we 're standing on unhallowed ground .
" Jerk . "
It 's Dud . Should never have fired him .
Where 's he been hiding ?
When tragedy strikes in a family , there 's a safety net .
It 's the safety net of community , of which we are all a part .
However , when tragedy reaches out and touches us all ... .
Sticking to the anemia , Jim ?
The family refused an autopsy .
It may have been anemia. I 'm not sure .
Whatever killed Danny Glick is being buried in that grave .
Ben Mears was in a motorcycle accident three years ago . A girl was killed .
Mears was cleared of all blame .
Kurt Barlow , antique dealer . That 's all they found on him .
- That 's it ? - On him .
Richard Thomas Straker , born in Tampa , Florida .
Expelled from UF in 1 966 for selling MDMA .
Charlie Rhodes is clean . The big surprise is the boy 's father .
Tony Glick filed for bankruptcy in 1 990 and left a lot of people in Nashua on the hook .
Thanks , Nolly .
- Your daughter called from Florida . - Danny !
Congratulations , boss .
- Stop this nonsense . - Aren 't you young to be a grandfather ?
Ed
I wanna pay my respects to Jack .
I feel guilty about last night .
I was upset and did something I shouldn 't have .
It 's my fault .
I 'm sorry , Ed .
- Hi , doctor . - Hi .
- l 'll see you later , Matt . - l can 't believe it .
- l used to babysit Danny Glick . - Yeah . Oh , how 's the baby ?
Poor little boy has a chest cold .
I don 't have the car , and Roy says doctors don 't make house calls anymore .
- He says they 're on a pedestal . - l didn 't say that .
Well , I wouldn 't say a pedestal , but I guess I could make a house call .
Ruth ?
Ruth .
It 's freezing in here .
I came home from school .
What 's wrong , honey ?
Are you sick ?
Why don 't you let me take that necklace off ?
No .
I had the strangest dream .
I was married to Dud Rogers .
He took me flying over town , and I saw a big fire .
- l saw you yelling up at me . - Dud Rogers ? The cripple ?
Sounds more like a nightmare .
You had Dud fired .
- That job was all he had . - The guy is a menace .
Can I get you something ?
No .
You sure ?
- Nothing ? - Not that !
Can 't you see I don 't feel good ?
Floyd ?
You there , Floyd ?
Come on .
Come on , we 'll get you inside . It 's too cold , too cold .
It 's okay , it 's okay .
What ?
Mike .
- Mikey ? - Are you staring at me ?
Mikey .
Your eyes are poked out .
Ears are missing .
Stop staring at me .
Damn you .
You will shut those eyes !
Damn you , shut those eyes !
I 'm a working mother. I can 't drive Mark to school. I need him on that bus .
I understand .
I spoke with Charlie Rhodes , and he seems to think
Mark knows a lot more about the dead dog than he 's saying .
He also thinks that Mark may be selling pot on the bus .
- That 's bull . - ls he crazy ? My God .
What 's the problem between you and Charlie ?
What , besides the fact I don 't have a father to kick his ass ?
Maybe I can speak to the principal at Mark 's school .
Maybe she can broker a truce .
You know what ? Don 't bother . The guy 's a moo-goo-gai maniac anyway .
What ?
You know , like , Vietnam , the ... .
Charlie was there . He shows us pictures on the bus .
He thinks he can , like , impress us or something .
Don 't lie about this , Mark .
He keeps them locked in his glove compartment .
Royce !
Royce , no !
You 're going to die . Are you ready to die , doctor ?
is my wife a whore ? If not , you think you can pump her for free ?
- No , no . - No , because she is a whore .
- Royce , baby , please- - - Shut up , Sandy . Shut the hell up !
That 's a $ 1 0,000 whore you just rolled off . You understand ?
Ten thousand tomorrow , or I pull this trigger .
Who 'd blame me ? Who 'd feel sorry for a dirty doctor ?
Okay ! Okay .
- Shut that thing up ! - lt 's okay , Roy. lt 's okay .
- Shut that thing up ! - What ? Royce , no !
- Here you go . - Thank you .
- Hi , guys . What can I get you ? - Hey , Susie , take a seat .
I 'm pretty busy now , Floyd .
Hi , Mike . How are you ?
- Well , I 'm fine , Susan . Thanks for asking . - So where you been , Susie ?
Working .
Can we talk about this another time ? Soon ?
- l think we have some things to talk about . - We do .
Oh , that was good , Floyd , but I think we can push a bit further .
My point being is , why doesn 't anyone here just , I don 't know , say the truth ?
What 's wrong with you ?
- He doesn 't feel well . - Come on , Floyd .
Tell her you 're pissed .
She got dumped by the writer
and she 's crawling back to homeboy .
- Knock it off . - What 's he saying ?
Floyd , tell her to kiss off , or tell her you love her .
At least say something real .
Look , this- - This isn 't fair , Susie .
Are you with me or with him ?
- Neither . - Who is this writer guy anyway ?
Come on . He 's the one you been reading about on her e-mails .
- l said , shut up ! - What e-mails ?
- Shut up , Mike . Shut up ! - Hang on , now . You two are friends .
- What kind of junk are you on , Mike ? - Nothing .
I 'm just sick . Sick of all that bullshit , anyway .
You upset about the funeral ?
I came back after everyone left .
I waited around a long time , and that 's when I must 've started to get sick .
Everything after that is gone .
What do you mean ?
I saw my mother 's eyes
which is pretty weird , because she 's dead .
My mother 's eyes watching me drown .
It was a pretty crazy dream .
Why do you say it was a dream ?
Look at my clothes , Mr. Burke .
- l must have fallen asleep in the dirt . - Come on , we 'll get out of here .
- You can sleep in my guest room . - l can drive .
Listen to your old teacher . You 're either sick or high .
So if you 're not better in the morning , I 'll drive you to the clinic .
Susan .
Could I speak to you for a minute , please ?
- l 've said all I have to say- - - But I haven 't .
- Please . - l think we 've had enough for one evening .
Mom , I 'll be right in .
I 'm not gonna stop writing the book , but I can change the name of the town .
I could change the state . The town was only meant to be a metaphor anyway .
- Then why choose Jerusalem 's Lot ? - Because this is the town I know .
It 's a town you think you know
and a town that thought it knew you .
He 'll be gone in a day , Susan . You 'll see .
Now that the truth is out .
Dud ?
Hey , Floyd .
- Where you been , gimp ? - l don 't limp anymore , Floyd .
And why not ?
Because I 'm different .
You were always different , Dud . Where you going ?
I 'm going to see Ruth Crockett .
Do yourself a favor . Stay clear .
Clear of them all . Bitches ain 't worth it .
I need some food , Floyd .
For Ruth .
I don 't know what the hell you 're talking about , Dud .
If you 're pissed with anyone , it should be Larry Crockett .
Mike and I always been good to you .
Especially Mike .
Dud ?
You seem a lot better now .
Yeah , the fresh air must 've sobered me up .
I have a sweatshirt for you , and sweatpants .
That door leads to the bathroom .
Thanks .
That
bruise looks painful .
Oh , yeah . You should 've seen the other guy .
Well
you should get it taken care of .
- Good night , Mike . - Good night .
Ralphie ?
Ralphie , where have you been ?
Yes .
Yes , of course you can come home . Please come home , Ralphie .
Mike .
Hello ?
Thank you for coming .
I 'm surprised you called me .
What you write is the least of my worries .
Well , is he alone ?
- He is now . - Maybe it 's an intruder .
- Did you call the police ? - No .
Not yet .
- l want you to see the body first . - The body ?
- You said he was acting strange . - He 's not moving .
Did you go in there ?
I peeked in , briefly .
Was he dead ?
- l don 't know . - Matt .
What the hell is going on here ? You didn 't kill him , did you ?
No . Of course not .
Mike ?
Mike Ryerson ?
You see ? Nothing .
Look at his chest . Loot at the bruise .
- There 's no bruise . - l saw it. lt has to be there .
He might be G 'd out on some designer drug .
Call an ambulance , the police and a lawyer , if you have one .
Hang on , hang on . Mike buried Danny Glick today .
There was a bruise on his chest . I saw it !
I heard talking in this room. I heard him open the window. I heard laughing .
I should have come in , but I was too scared .
Your intruder would have to be a fireman to climb up .
Ben , I know what I heard .
I wanted to tell you before everyone starts calling me crazy .
Okay , let 's get this done .
Handsome corpse . You sure he 's dead ?
Atypical lividity , but he 's dead all right .
- Sorry to drag you into this . - Don 't be .
- l don 't know why you did , though . - lf l told you , you 'd have me committed .
Maybe we should move down the hall a bit . Could be some kind of contagious disease .
is it similar to what killed Danny Glick ? Acute anemia ?
We 'll leave that for the lab coats , but there 's no immediate sign of foul play .
As for that intruder you heard ... .
- You have a 1 2-foot ladder in your garage ? - No .
You heard Mr. Ryerson 's voice and some laughter .
- Could it have been his laughter ? - lt sounded like a child .
You said he slept here because he was acting loopy and started a fight .
- Yeah ? - Some people laugh when they 're drunk .
They 'll run some toxicology tests on his blood .
How did you get involved in this , Mr. Mears ?
Matt called me .
Close friends ?
Literary men .
See , most people find a body , and they call the police . You called a writer .
i should 've pulled that trigger . You 're finished , Cody .
Banks don 't open until nine , Royce .
- Look , I 'm with a dead body here , okay- - - You 're gonna be the dead body .
My wife came to you professionally !
- i 'm calling the medical board ! - Don 't call the board .
Don 't call the board .
That 's not gonna help anybody . I need time to shift some funds .
I just bought a car .
You 'll have your 1 0 grand by tomorrow .
You okay ?
Pupillary contraction . Gets me every time .
- Were you waiting for me ? - No , sir . Run along , Mark .
Anything unusual ? A van parked along side the road ?
Oh , Ben , I heard about Mike Ryerson . What happened ?
- Nobody knows . - Ann Norton called .
She has some things to say about the book .
- l don 't have to look for a new room , do I ? - No , no . You could write a chapter on me .
Thanks .
Ed , where were you all night ?
Blowing off steam . Hope I worried you sick .
I 've been thinking about us , Ed .
is that right ? What have you been thinking , Miss Prunier ?
Weasel , got some beer , if you give me a hand .
Breakfast of champions .
Parkins , I want my phone call !
Let me out of here !
- Let me out of here ! - Shut up !
Do you think these bars will hold me , Mears ? I 'll see you tonight !
Yeah , I 'm really scared ! Why don 't you bring your rubber gloves ? !
No wonder she broke up with you !
If that 's what you wear to a fight , what do you wear to bed ? !
Who do you think was in the room with him ?
I have my suspicions .
I 'm holding back , lest peop- -
Call me crazy . There 's someone upstairs .
You 're sure ?
I know my house . There 's someone up there .
You hear ?
Call the police .
- Matt . - Not yet .
Start talking . About anything .
Well , you won 't get any argument from me . I completely agree .
You hope he gets run out of town ?
You 're totally right . He can 't be trusted .
He did deceive you . He deceived all of us .
- -and then they just turn out to be someone completely different .
Mr. Burke .
Mike .
- What happened to you ? - Look at me .
Mr. Burke . Look at me .
- l know why you invited me here . - Go away , Mike .
- l can feel the way you look at me . - l revoke your invitation to this house .
Mike , in the name of God Almighty
leave .
Wouldn 't it be a relief to touch me , just once ?
Then I can touch you .
- Look at me . - You 're dead , Mike !
- What happened to me ? - You died , Mike . You died .
You died yesterday .
You 're a monster , a nightmare ... .
No . No , that can 't be .
Go away , Mike . Go away .
No !
Matt ?
Matt !
No , no ! No !
- Lights out . - Let me out of here ! Let me out of here !
- What am I being charged with ? - Drunk and disorderly .
Mears .
Oh , Mears .
- You wanna finish this , Mears ? - Go to sleep ...
- ... before I charge you with assault . - You 're a coward , Mears .
You 'll never be a Bloody Pirate .
What did you say ?
Marjorie ... .
Ralph !
Mark .
Open the window .
Come on , Mark . Open the window .
Mark .
Open the window , Mark .
It 's not just me , Mark . He commands .
Mark , I 'm cold out here . Open the window .
Mark .
Now I lay me down to sleep , I pray the Lord my soul to keep ... .
What do you want ? !
Let me in , Mark . Come on .
Open the window
or I 'll try another one .
Okay , come in .
I 'll kill you , Petrie , and your mother !
Ben Mears , I can see you through the grate .
Here I come , Mears . Almost there .
I see your knees shaking and the piss running down your leg .
What 's it gonna take to make you face me ?
Go to sleep , Tibbits .
Sleep ? I 'm wide awake .
I 'll be awake all night .
You 're not in the vent .
Of course I am .
I squeezed and slithered to reach you .
I broke my collarbones and hips , Mears , but I 'm getting there .
I 'm getting closer .
Look at me ! Look at me , Mears ! Invite me in !
We 'll finish this fight. I 'll rip your heart out . I 'll squeeze it and drink your blood !
- Leave me alone ! - Invite me in , Mears .
Hail Mary , full of grace ...
- ... help me win this stock-car race . - Damn .
That 's quite a story .
They said you was a writer , but l- -
You gonna sit with him your whole shift ?
Wait .
There 's more .
Think I 'm gonna stay a little longer .
is he gonna make it ?
The fall ruptured his spleen . Pulmonary and myocardial contusions .
But he can talk .
I hear that , but whatever Mr. Mears says now could be his last testament .
Please , don 't go .
No one awake knew the truth .
A handful might have suspected , but even their suspicions were vague and unformed .
Monday was garbage day on Jointner Ave .
Today the green bags lay scattered on the curb .
The library was closed , so was the New Look Salon .
Now the light spilled across the land , and all the evil things slept .
The untouched walked slowly in Jerusalem 's Lot
as if their bodies had become glassy and fragile .
They turned on all their lights , and they did not look out their windows .
That above all else , they did not look out their windows .
Free to go , Mr. Mears .
Miss Norton will drive you home .
You are being released , but I advise you to watch your step
in Jerusalem 's Lot .
What about Tibbits ? is he still in there ?
- He 's still with us . - lf you want to press charges ...
- ... Deputy Gardener will assist you . - l 'm fine . Let 's go .
This isn 't like Floyd . He 's not the violent type .
What did you tell Floyd about my past ? How does he know about the house ...
- ... and the Bloody Pirates ? - What are you talking about ?
I 'm only here because Matt Burke had a heart attack .
Let 's see if he has any ideas about Mike Ryerson 's death ...
- ... and the missing Glick boy . - Floyd ?
Floyd , get up .
Holy- -
- What the hell 's going on here ? - He 's chewed his own wrists .
- Barry ? - Jim .
Hey , how 'd it go the other night ? Did you stuff that little Sandy McDougall ?
Actually , Barry , I 'm in a little trouble .
- Can I ask you for a loan ? - How much ?
Ten grand . Only for a week . Just until I liquidate some assets .
You know that Beemer 's really drank up all my cash .
Yeah , it 's just that I 've dumped everything into T-bills .
Give me a couple of days to round something up- -
l don 't have a couple of days . I kind of- -
Sorry to put you on the spot like this . Thanks anyway .
I 'll be outside .
I confirmed you 've had a mild heart attack .
The good news is your heart will continue to function just fine .
At your age a myocardial infarction can be induced by a number of things :
- Diet , cholesterol , smoking- - - And fear .
Jim , I want you to help me
or commit me right now .
Now , these guys already think I 'm crazy .
Why 's that , Matt ?
I had a heart attack because I was scared .
Scared to death .
I saw Mike Ryerson in my house .
Well , that 's understandable .
Mike died in your house .
You 've suffered some trauma .
Sometimes we see things- -
- Jim , did you perform the autopsy on Mike ? - No . No , I did not .
He had his shirt off . He had two cuts .
Vertical on the chest . Horizontal on the stomach .
Maybe one was a mistake , or the ME decided to dig deeper .
- Find out why Mike had two cuts , okay ? - All right .
- There 's more . - Matt has asked me to go to the church
to get some holy water .
Are they still talking ?
Matt is .
The more he talks , the more afraid I get .
Of vampires ?
No , for Matt . He 's talking himself straight into the loony bin .
Whatever 's going on , Matt Burke isn 't crazy .
I never thought so either .
Susan , I have friends in New York . You could go and stay .
Get away for a long weekend .
- No . Thanks . - Let Matt and the police sort this out .
If something 's going on , I wanna help .
I misled you about the book .
But not about my feelings .
Go on , Mears . Don 't be a chicken .
You wanna be a Bloody Pirate ?
i wanted to be a Bloody Pirate , so i entered the Marsten house .
You 're not a Pirate till you bring something back .
- Unless he kills you . - if Hubie kills you , you 're in .
That night , it poisoned my life .
Everything changed after that night .
i could hear things scuttling away from me on the other side of the plaster .
Living things . Rats or woodchucks or whatever else
that had been nesting in walls or hibernating in cellars .
i could have left quickly , but i didn 't .
i wanted to prove myself , so i went upstairs .
The house smelled . Mildew and upholstery rot .
And the kind of rancid smell like butter that had gone over .
i kept thinking i heard footsteps behind me . i was afraid to turn around
because i might see Hubie Marsten shambling after me with a carving knife .
Even then it was the house of legend and nightmare .
i didn 't walk. i ran to Hubie 's bedroom and grabbed my souvenir .
And that 's when Hubie came home .
i knew the rumors . Whispers that Hubie Marsten kidnapped
and sacrificed small children to his infernal gods .
The campfire tales of torture and worse .
i fled to the bedroom and hid in a closet .
Hubie was coming my way . i pulled at the door
desperately trying to close it , but it stuck on a garment bag .
Hubie entered the room
and i watched the rest .
Hubie was not alone in the bedroom that night .
- String up . - Something was with him .
Something i never saw , but could only define as a presence .
- No more . - Hubie was on his knees .
He sobbed and begged for his life .
Whatever it was , didn 't seem to listen .
Hubie 's wife , Birdie , lay on the bathroom floor .
Legs splayed , bare feet
chest yawning from a shotgun blast .
Then the impossible .
Help me .
i collapsed. i was paralyzed .
Through frozen lips , Birdie Marsten cried :
" " Help me . Help me . " "
Birdie 's cries continued all night .
And i could not move .
Something in that house loomed above me and laughed .
Aunt Cynthia found me the next morning , rambling about Birdie 's ghost .
My aunt checked inside the bathroom , where i was afraid to go .
The cries heard that night weren 't Birdie Marsten or any ghost .
Ronnie Barnes , the boy in the bathtub .
Yes .
Cynthia told me not to talk about the crying .
That it wouldn 't have helped him anyway .
So I lied .
And then I said I never heard Ronnie .
Everyone felt sorry for me . They even said I was brave .
- You were 9 years old . - But I could have saved that kid .
That 's why I came back . That 's the book I have to write .
Small-town lies . My lies .
What about the house ? You said there was a presence .
And it scares me , even to this day .
I think it was my own cowardice laughing at me .
Ben , you 're no coward .
I 'm the one who can 't leave home .
Maybe I will go to New York , Mr. Mears .
If you 'll come with me .
This time I have to stay .
Could 've been fun . Now we 're stuck with Matt Van Helsing .
Shall we go check him for puncture wounds ?
Mr. Zazelka left his lesson plan for you .
He 's sick today , along with quite a few others .
Something must be going around .
Vampires .
Well , maybe we should scrap the lesson plan and do some creative writing .
I didn 't think you 'd make it to school .
Don 't tell me you 're sick after you were out all night .
Where were you ?
- What 's gotten into you ? - What , or who ?
You 're grounded , Ruth . I don 't care if you think it 's unfair .
I 'm still your father .
Oh , is that your choice , or do you still want it both ways ?
Who is it ?
- Who is what ? - Who were you with last night ?
My boyfriend .
Dud Rogers !
Ruth . No .
Rogers !
I 'll kill you !
- l 'm surprised you 're going along with this . - Well , I don 't believe in vampires .
But I have to accept that people are dying of anemia . What 's your excuse ?
Professional curiosity .
I don 't know how , but Matt Burke was right about Mike Ryerson 's autopsy .
There were two incisions on his body .
I think the police should take a good look at Floyd Tibbits .
He attacked me yesterday . He was wearing a hat .
Floyd Tibbits is dead .
He chewed through his own wrists in jail last night .
I think he might have drank his own blood .
- Hello . Father Callahan ? - Yes .
- Father , I 'm Susan Norton . - Won 't you come in .
I 'm not a Catholic or anything .
I have an odd request from Matt Burke
a teacher in town who 's not a Catholic either .
He would like some ... .
Could you please just visit Matt Burke in room 3A over at the hospital ?
Sure .
is there something else you 'd like to say ?
No . Definitely not .
What are you gonna tell the Glicks ?
I want to exhume their son . Check for infectious encephalitis .
It 's the only explanation .
Some people think the Marsten house is involved .
When something bad happens in this town people always look to the Marsten house .
It 's been that way since I can remember .
Marjorie died this morning .
They took her husband Tony to the hospital .
He 's in shock .
Where 's Marjorie 's body ?
- Should be the county coroner 's . - My daughter spoke with the police .
Chief Gillespie took Marjorie to the funeral home
on account of no one knows where Carl Foreman is .
- Who 's he ? - He 's the coroner .
Larry , Chief Gillespie .
Parkins , you better do something about Dud Rogers .
I want that cripple out of town .
I 've been speaking with the town clerk 's office .
I don 't give a rat 's ass .
Dud Rogers is stalking my daughter . I want something done .
You might ask him about that missing Glick kid too .
We 've been going over land transactions
for the Marsten house and the Laundromat .
It 's clear that Richard Straker did not buy the Marsten house .
- You did . - So ?
In return , Straker 's corporation gave your corporation thirty acres
in Kennebunk , which , once that new Crystal Mall is built
will be worth 20 times the house and Laundromat .
Now , why would Straker swing such a lopsided deal ?
- You 'll have to ask him . - l will , but right now I 'm asking you .
Whatever business I have with Richard Straker or anyone else is confidential .
Who is Richard Straker , Larry ?
An antique dealer , as far as I know .
- Where is Kurt Barlow ? - l believe he 's in Europe .
- What 's happening to this town ? - How do I know ?
Ask Dud Rogers .
Now , are you gonna straighten out that gimp , or am I gonna do it myself ?
Don 't think that I won 't .
What ?
- What are you looking at ? - Floyd Tibbits died in my jail today .
Tibbits ?
You ain 't worth a piss hole in the snow .
Get the hell out of here .
Well , if you 're gonna accuse me of something , then do it !
Why did you buy that house for Straker ?
You son of a bitch. I 'll have you- -
What 's going on , Larry ? Why did you buy that house ?
None of your business .
Why did you buy that house ?
Straker said he wouldn 't buy the damn house .
He wouldn 't buy his way into any town .
He had to be invited .
Invited ?
He had to be invited ?
Larry , what have you done ?
Have you noticed anything out of the ordinary in town lately ?
The mortality rate is certainly on the rise .
It 's getting higher .
Any explanation ?
Vampires ?
It 's difficult to proceed as it is .
But it 's gonna be more difficult if you think I have sickbed dementia .
On the contrary , you seem extremely lucid .
Lucidity doesn 't presuppose sanity , does it , Father ?
No , it doesn 't .
- First were the two Glick boys . - And then their mother .
- Marjorie Glick died this morning . - Mike Ryerson .
Floyd Tibbits . And Carl Foreman is missing .
He 's the county coroner .
He and his wife are in my parish .
Have you considered the possibility of vampirism ?
Well , that 's a rather novel diagnosis .
Really ? I 'd say it was a very old diagnosis .
The church 's concept of evil has radically transformed
this last century , Matthew .
We still acknowledge Satan and the demons
but we see them now mostly as aspects of the human psyche .
- Blame that on Freud . - Freud ?
Oh , yeah , you 're right . He did spoil all the fun .
The good thing about this remote possibility is it 's easy to prove .
I also don 't need you to believe . Not yet .
A doctor from here and a very astute writer
are investigating the possibility right now , even as we speak .
The only thing I ask is that if they return
with evidence of vampirism
can we count on your immediate and unwavering support ?
I 'm always available to help you , Matthew .
Sorry I 'm late .
Susan , Susan . Floyd Tibbits is dead .
What ?
Floyd had a fight with Ben . They put Floyd in the drunk tank .
- l know- - - Well , Floyd killed himself in jail .
- He slit his wrists . - No .
It 's terrible . You stay away from that writer , Susan .
- This is crazy . - And you 're right in the middle .
It doesn 't look- - l don 't care how it looks , Susan .
I just don 't want you hurt .
Floyd slit his wrists ?
Poor Floyd . He must have had second thoughts .
I hear he tried to stop the bleeding . It 's terrible . He drank his own blood .
Would you say there 's money in literature ?
You plan on writing a book on this ?
No , I was just being rude .
- Frank . - Hey , Jimmy . Good to see you .
- Did they ever find the other boy ? - No , they didn 't .
Poor woman must have died of heartbreak .
- She your patient , Jimmy ? - No , no .
But her condition is strikingly similar to Mike Ryerson .
No surface lividity , no rigor . No incipient rigor .
Frank .
- l 'd like to sit with her tonight . - Sit with her ?
There 's a strange virus going around .
Look , it could be infectious encephalitis .
But either way I 'm gonna need some time to observe the decomposition process .
Well , whatever you want .
Be sure to lock the door when you leave .
Well , of course . Thank you .
It 's a tragedy .
- Norton 's Cafe . - Hi .
- ls Susan there ? - Susan 's left work , Ben .
Did she say where she was going ?
No . She got a little upset ...
- ... when she heard about Floyd . - Does she have a cell phone ?
- l 'm afraid not . - Thank you .
- lt 's all right . - Who are you ?
I 'm Mark Petrie. I know you . You 're Sue Norton . My mother knows your father .
Joyce Petrie. lt 's my mother . The waitress at Giaco 's .
- What are you doing here ? - What are you doing here ?
Did you come to kill the vampires ?
- A friend died last night . - One of them tried to get me .
That was Richard Straker in the SUV . He 's moving around by day
so he must be the watchdog .
The vampire 's name is Barlow . And he 's the partner that nobody 's seen yet .
You 're not the only one talking about vampires .
- Who else ? - A teacher and a doctor .
- You okay ? - lt 's that house .
A writer friend of mine spent a horrific night there when he was a kid .
- Ben Mears ? - You know him ?
I know the story . Did you bring a stake too ?
Yeah . That 's cool , but I don 't think it 's going to work .
Don 't believe everything you read .
Come in .
- Hello , Father . - Ed , come in . Have a seat .
We have something to celebrate today , Father .
- What would that be ? - Eva Prunier has agreed to marry me .
- Well , congratulations . - Persistence and patience .
And love . Nothing good ever happens without love .
We 'd like to do it tomorrow . A small ceremony . Very simple .
- That is , if you 're available . - lt would be an honor .
I 've had some good news meself .
Unusual , but good . A true battle .
Perhaps there 's a need for this religious relic after all . Care for a Jameson 's ?
Never say no .
Here 's to your marriage and the death of Freud .
- Slainte . - Father , maybe I 'll wait on this drink ...
- ... what with the wedding tomorrow and all . - No . Has she 's reformed you already ?
Perhaps I 'll abstain as well .
Closed .
Closed all day .
Thank you .
Stop . We 'll call the police .
- l have friends who can help . - No .
I 'm going in before that kid comes back to my window .
- l 'll go . You keep watch . - No , thanks .
When we find him , don 't look into his eyes , okay ?
He sleeps in a coffin until dark , but he can still hook you with his eyes .
Do you hear what you 're saying ? Do you really believe this ?
What if Barlow is just an ordinary serial killer ?
You wish .
- Oh , God , do you smell that ? - Yes .
- lt 's worse in here , isn 't it ? - Yes .
That 's where we have to go .
- l can hear my heart . - l can hear your heart too .
Mark . Oh , no .
The police are on their way . That was an alarm you triggered .
- We-- - Don 't come any closer .
Just take whatever it is you have and leave .
- We 're not stealing anything . We 're just- - - What do you want ?
- Are there more of you ? - No . Look , I 'm sorry .
We were curious about the house .
We heard it was sold , but we didn 't think anyone lived here .
You 're trespassing .
What does he have there ? You 're armed .
- lt 's just a hammer and some wood . - A hammer ?
You 've come to vandalize ?
No , look , I 'm Susan Norton . I 've lived in Salem 's Lot my whole life .
This is Mark Petrie . We know you just moved here , and- -
And this is the way you welcome me ? With hammers and guns ?
You
show me that .
What is this ?
is this a weapon ? is it ?
- No . - ls it ?
No !
Fine !
- Help ! Help ! - Go on !
- Help ! - Three .
Two .
Help !
One . Time 's up .
Oh , this is ridiculous .
I 'm killing my career .
I 'm being blackmailed .
Professionally ?
It was very unprofessional on my part .
If you saw the man 's wife , you might think it was understandable
but certainly not professional or forgivable .
I 'm surprised . I didn 't think doctors had penises .
Yeah , it 's an industry secret .
We usually try to keep it between ourselves and the nurses .
How much ?
Ten thousand , by today .
He threatened to call the board earlier .
I might not even be a doctor right now .
You 're too busy to be a doctor . You 're a vampire hunter .
- We should be home by midnight . - That would be Cinderella .
I can 't stay any longer. lt 's useless . I gotta go find Susan .
What if she went up to the house ?
Oh , my God .
Ralphie ?
Where are you , sweetheart ?
Marge ? You okay ?
Use the cross !
She bit me !
She bit me ! She bit me !
Give me my bag ! Give me my bag !
She bit me .
Tetanus .
In my heart .
Do it ! Hurry up !
Did we get it ?
You should call me in the morning .
Hello ?
Susan !
Ben , there 's no car . Would she really come up here by herself ?
If you think so , we 'll go in . If not , we should find her .
We 'll come back together with a plan .
You wanna be a Bloody Pirate , don 't you ? Go on , Mears .
- Unless he kills you . - if Hubie kills you , you 're in !
Susan !
Ben , come on .
Call Norton 's . Let 's check her house .
Help ! Help me , please !
- Help ! - Here I come , ready or not .
Where are you ?
- Susan ! - Mark ?
I can 't see. lt 's so dark .
- Come down , boy . - l know your name !
- l admire you . Come down for a taste . - lt 's Barlow !
There 's enough here for two . Why would you run , boy ?
Susan !
i 'd like to drop everything and help , Ben , but i have four missing people
and three dead .
When was the last time you heard from Susan ?
- lt was about nine hours ago . - That 's not so long .
I 've been to her house , the cafe , the gym , the library . Nobody knows where she is .
What 's going on , Mr. Mears ? Do you know ? Because i don 't .
i have suspicions , but if i don 't know , i can 't help .
You wouldn 't believe me .
Ben ?
Be careful , Parkins .
Susan ?
Closed. lt was closed yesterday too .
Thanks .
Thank you kindly .
Ed , breakfast is ready .
Ed ?
Yeah ?
is there a writer here named Ben ?
- Ben Mears . - Yeah , could you get him ?
- Please ? - He may be sleeping .
No , he 'd want you to wake him up . Please .
Morning .
- Are you the friend of Sue Norton ? - Yes . Have you seen her ?
Ben .
- Ben , have you seen Ed this morning ? - No , I haven 't .
- We 're getting married today . - Married ?
- Can I talk to you outside ? - Of course .
Congratulations .
We went in the house through that window .
She 's still up there ! Right now . Look , I don 't know what she ... .
l 'm with Mark Petrie . He was with her . I 'm headed there now .
You can 't barge in. i can get a warrant ...
- ... within the hour . - Stop .
I gotta go , chief. I 'll call you back .
Father , with what Mark says and Susan 's car , that 's proof enough for me .
Hold on a minute . What if Straker 's partner is armed ?
How are you gonna protect yourself ?
I made these up last night .
- Take that . - Son , stay in the car .
I 'm going .
- Maybe you 'd rather stay behind , Father . - No , I 'll go . This team needs a clear head .
Vampires . Would have been a lot easier to accept
if you could have arranged for a thunderstorm or a power failure .
Would a dancing Marjorie Glick do it for you ?
It 's a loan .
Ten thousand ? I can 't take this from you .
When this is over , we 're gonna need your good reputation .
- Thanks , man . - You guys hear about the hippie vampire ?
He 's ghoul , man . Real ghoul .
- You 're doing well , Ben . - Oh , yeah ? How so ?
Only a trained physician can see that you 're scared out of your mind .
I 've never been up here before , at least not this close .
Hold on .
Let cooler heads prevail .
Hello ?
- Hello ? - Susan !
Hello !
Straker 's upstairs .
There 's something different .
- He 's bled dry . - Holy Mother of God .
I didn 't do that .
I tried to go down , but I didn 't .
I know what 's different .
It doesn 't smell anymore .
Over here .
Give me the stake .
Hold on . You have to make sure .
If he 's dead , you 're only desecrating a corpse . But if he 's not ... .
Legally dead .
Saints preserve us .
Here !
My God . What monster did this ?
She 's dead .
Or undead .
Wait ! Wait !
What if we kill Barlow and they all come back to life ?
Or they just die .
- You don 't really believe that . - But what if ?
Please , not Susan . We know where she is .
We can come back if we have to .
- What if she infects someone else ? - Please .
Please .
It 's been a gruesome day .
Rest in peace .
- Who 's poking around the Marsten house ? - Can 't say from this distance .
Town looks a little dead today .
Maybe I 'll take a ride up and see .
They 're leaving , Nolly . Let it be .
Sometimes these badges get in the way .
Our badges ? What do you mean ?
- Are you all right , Parkins ? - No .
I 'm scared .
On lighter occasions , these used to hold the perfect martini .
There 's a presence in that house . I don 't know if you can feel it .
Oh , I can feel it .
I felt it before , when I was a boy and I went inside .
I thought it was me. I thought it was
some manifestation of my own fear .
It wasn 't .
- What is it ? - The unholy spirit .
Dull , mindless , moronic evil .
As familiar in the confessional as the smell of old velvet .
Marsten invited the unholy spirit into his house and home , and there it resides .
In that house , it feels so familiar . It feels like it 's coming from inside me .
Evil comes from inside of all of us .
I 've made a fine career turning the hard mirror on other people .
Would you feel more comfortable in the confessional ?
I don 't need absolution , Father . I need peace of mind .
I 'm weak .
I let a boy die once .
Out of fear .
I could have saved him , and instead I lied .
And now my lies have grown like a cancer .
And as much as I can , I hate myself .
You 're way beyond hate now , Ben , and into truth .
Truth with yourself is the first step towards forgiveness .
Truth with the Lord follows .
Five Hail Marys , two Our Fathers and an act of contrition .
That was a fine confession .
Hi , Sandy. ls Royce here ?
Jimmy , I 'm sorry about this .
Yeah , me too .
Royce ?
Got my money ?
Look , Royce , I 'm sorry . I don 't know what else to say .
Just give me my money .
- l should have known . - But you didn 't .
Men grow old , but never old enough to know better .
Royce , are you feeling all right ?
Oh , now he wants to get down my pants too . Get lost .
- Has he been acting strange lately ? - What ?
- Get the hell out of here . - Listen to me .
There 's a virus going around . You should come to the hospital for an exam .
Then let me take Sandy and Roy in for the vaccination .
- Get out . - Just get out of here . Go !
My car. I 'll give you my brand new BMW if you let me take Roy to the hospital .
- You 're not taking my baby . - Shut up , Sandy .
You 're gonna give me your Beemer ? For keeps ?
Yeah . Keys for keys , my car for yours . I just wanna get Roy vaccinated .
- You can pick him up tomorrow . - Give him the kid .
- Royce ! - Give him the frigging kid .
Come on .
Come on !
He 's fine. I just want a complete physical and a full blood check .
- Who is he ? - He 's my nephew .
Why don 't you register him under my name . Okay ?
- Told Matt what happened at the house ? - He confirmed what I already knew .
Well , it 's an epidemic now .
I don 't know the pathology , how it starts or spreads .
You know how it spreads .
But why do they need blood ?
Do they lack the capacity to generate red blood cells ?
We put kidney patients on erythropoietin when dialysis chews up their red-cell count .
Maybe a 30-day trial would cure one of these beings
if we could stop them from killing long enough .
Hear what I 'm trying to say ? I don 't know how to stop it .
Start with Barlow . He 's the root . And then we work our way back .
Finding Barlow may not be so easy . He 's experienced .
- He 'll be clever . - Where 's Mark and Father Callahan ?
- They went to get Mark 's mother . - Convincing his mother will take time .
- lt 's almost dark . - Which city , please ?
Jerusalem 's Lot . Petrie . This is the last time we split up .
Hello ? Mark , get over here . Come here .
- Mom ! - Hello ?
Whatever you 've been doing with Mark does not sound right at all .
Can we continue this debate at the hospital ?
- We have to hurry . - There 's blood on his clothes , Father .
Did you really pound a stake through a man 's body ? And the two boys ?
Mark .
- Mark . - Stop , stop .
There 's blood in your hair .
You 've involved my son in a crime , Father . I know about you .
- You have a reputation with the bottle . - Mom , he didn 't do anything !
Father , I want you to leave ! I 'm gonna call the police .
- l don 't wanna see you with Mark again . - Please !
Call Dr. Cody and Ben Mears . They were- - God , the fricking phone is dead .
Give me that ! Hello ? What- - ?
Mom ?
In God 's name !
Back away . Back away , shaman .
- Let him go . - Piss off ! You get out of the room ...
- ... and I 'll save his life . - No .
- He killed my attendant . He can replace him . - Stop !
Why ?
Will you sacrifice your little cross ? Throw it away .
Throw it away .
Meet me on even terms . Black against white .
- Your faith against mine . - And trust you to let him go ?
Run , Mark .
Go on , run !
Your turn , Father .
The crucifix .
Drop it .
You stay away from me .
I 'm a priest .
I command you , in the name of God .
The demands of your church are impossible . It 's all about sacrifice and no proof .
Nothing to sink your teeth into . Isn 't that terribly lonely ?
Kneel , Father .
Kneel .
Say a prayer if you have to . Confide in me . Where did you go wrong ?
Was it a little nip over lunch ?
Some wine with dinner ?
Drugs ? Little boys ?
You 're not ready to go to heaven . You know it .
You 'd welcome death . Instead I 'll have you serve as a mortal .
Life is such a precious gift . So have a drink on me .
Enjoy the present .
Drink .
Did I do the right thing with my life ? Was I mislead ? You know , don 't you ?
is there a God ?
Whoever feeds you
is your God .
Eva .
I 'm sorry I 'm late .
- l can 't enter . - What is it , Ed ?
It 's different , is all .
It 's wonderful and strong .
Are you different , Ed ?
Yes and no .
I love you even more .
Join me , Eva .
It 's all right , Ed .
I love you .
All those years .
I should never have made you wait .
This is my choice .
Sons of whores .
Hey , Petrie !
You come on out of there ! I know it 's you !
Come on !
All right .
I hear you .
According to literature , a vampire can 't simply walk into a man 's house .
He has to be invited .
Mike Ryerson invited Danny Glick into my home. I invited Mike- -
He killed my mom . He killed my mom . She 's dead .
Hello ?
Sorry to call so late .
i 'm glad you did , Daddy .
i 'm up every three hours to feed little Connor anyway .
i wish you were here in Florida .
Me too .
I 'm trying to decide ... .
Decide how much they need me here .
They 'll always need you , but i need you too .
- Little Connor wants to see his grandpa . - Yeah .
The weather 's good for golfing , Daddy .
Don 't wait forever .
He just amazes me . He 's a tough kid . Tougher than I was at his age .
You 're tough enough .
- You haven 't tried to leave us . - Don 't tempt me .
How long will he sleep ?
Till morning .
I can 't promise what shape he 'll be in when the sedative wears off .
- What do you think of his story ? - l think it 's true .
- You think Barlow climbs walls ? - That may be an illusion .
I wouldn 't be surprised if Barlow flew in like a damn bat .
You think he got Callahan ?
I think Father Callahan would be here if he could .
You have to find Barlow tomorrow .
- To kill the serpent , you cut off the head . - Where do we start ? The antique store ?
Too obvious .
Mark said Barlow picked him up by the neck .
That chalk ?
Could he be in the school ?
Junior high is close . So is Butler Elementary .
He could hide in a furnace room or storage area .
Schools are abandoned at night . He could move freely .
That 's where you have to concentrate .
Take Mark with you . He 'll be a diversion .
- Don 't you think he 's been through enough ? - Think about it .
Two adults snooping around a school ? How long before someone calls the police ?
Use the boy . Use everything you have , Ben . And be prepared to lie .
If you two get locked up , we 're finished .
- He 's right . - lf you haven 't considered it already
consider it now . There is every possibility that some of us or all of us
may live and triumph only to stand trial for murder .
We can 't go in there now .
We should check where he was last seen . We may find another lead .
My house .
I 'm all right . Let 's just get him .
You have family around here ?
An aunt in California .
Would it help to go back in and see your mom ?
Maybe there 's something you 'd like to take ?
- Parkins . We need your help , Parkins . - Too late for that .
My deputy didn 't show up today . Somehow don 't think he will .
- Where are you going ? - None of your business .
Parkins , this town 's dying .
- But we still have a chance . - This town 's dying
because something terrible was born .
Something between Marsten and whatever games he played in that house .
That 's why Barlow came here .
Ask Larry Crockett . He 's the son of a bitch who invited him .
Barlow 's a killer . He 's a monster .
We think he killed the Glick brothers , Mike Ryerson- -
Marjorie Glick , Dud Rogers , Charlie Rhodes Floyd Tibbits , Carl Foreman
maybe even Susie Norton .
He 's not just a killer , is he ?
No .
I 'm not afraid to die , Mr. Mears . Not at all .
But these people don 't die , do they ?
Hello , Father .
Hey , Father .
Thought we lost you .
You ... .
You did , boy !
I thought I 'd make you taste your own medicine .
It hurts , doesn 't it !
Crockett ? Crockett !
Larry ! Larry !
How many pills did you take , Larry ? Larry , look at me . How many pills ?
- We 're looking for Kurt Barlow . - You sold him the house .
Ruthie 's gone .
He flew out the window with my daughter , and they laughed at me .
Was it him ?
It was Dud Rogers ! Dud Rogers and Ruth Crockett .
Ruthie Crockett .
Get him in the light . See if he 's one of them .
What do you know about Barlow ? You sold him the house !
- Chief Parkins says you invited him ! - l didn 't know. I swear I didn 't know .
- Look , let 's just go , okay ? It 's getting late . - You get out .
You can 't judge me !
I don 't give a damn about your forgiveness !
Get out ! This is my house ! My house ! And I 'll destroy it if I want to !
The white chalk could be dry wall .
They 're renovating my boarding house .
Are you saying the chalk on his shirt was dry wall ?
We gotta check hardware stores , construction site- -
lt 's only two miles from the Marsten house .
The lady at the boarding house asked about Ed . Said he was missing .
The Marsten house , the boarding house , construction site- - Barlow can be anywhere .
There are five people living in this house with me and no one 's answering . Let 's go .
What 's the alternative , Jim ?
You wanna leave ?
I 'm not saying that .
But this isn 't gonna be over today , Ben .
It 'll be weeks before we get to them all , if we get to them all .
Can you stand that ?
Can you stand doing what we did to Mike 1 000 times ?
Pulling them out of closets , their stinking holes
only to ram stakes into their chest cavities and smash their hearts ?
Can you stand that without going nuts ?
And what about Mark ?
- You think he can take it ? - We 're wasting time .
Matt Burke says that the good in this town far outweighs the bad .
- And what side was I on ? - l think you have a choice .
- Oh , God . - He 's here .
I 'll get a flashlight .
Cody !
Oh , God !
No !
They cut the wood .
He 's here .
I can feel it .
Use a hammer !
Oh , my God .
We have to hurry . Pull it into the light .
Give me the hammer .
He looks like a regular guy . Could be someone 's father .
Don 't look at him .
I said , don 't look at him !
- No ! - Mark ! No !
Mark !
Fame .
Money , women .
Think . You 're the writer .
Killing me will never kill the evil in a man , nor yourself .
Think . You will always be flawed until you embrace evil .
You don 't have the guts to put that stake where it belongs .
You will always be weak within .
Think , writer . Desperate man
sucking tales from whom you meet .
Feeding on the lives of family and friend .
Spinning their tragedy into personal gold .
I know where you 're going with this .
You are the vampire .
I 'm not the vampire .
Not anymore , you son of a bitch !
Look at me .
He 's gone .
I think they 're dead .
Go on and get in the car .
- Ben . - Susan .
Did you kill him ?
Why didn 't it help you ?
I don 't need any help .
I only need you to be happy .
- May I come in ? - No .
Ben , this isn 't your house .
And you 're not a religious man .
You don 't have any faith to keep me out .
You 're wrong .
I do have faith .
You pushed me to it .
Oh , Sue .
I wish you 'd never gone in that house without me .
I was stupid .
Reckless .
I did something for you , Ben . I was so excited to tell you .
I went to the hospital .
After I saw Father Callahan .
I found the records of the boy from the Marsten house .
Do you know how he died ?
- Very slowly . - No .
He was strangled . He died instantly from a crushed larynx .
Ronnie Barnes was never alive that night .
You couldn 't have saved him .
The crying you heard wasn 't him .
I don 't understand .
Even at 9 years old , you had a good imagination .
I could love you , Ben Mears .
I feel it .
No , Susan .
I 'm sorry .
You 've been sorry long enough . It 's time you forgive yourself .
Ben ! Ben , they 're everywhere !
Susan , no !
Ben .
We gotta go .
Crockett !
- They 're everywhere . - Come on !
He 's right- - ! Look out ! Look out !
Ruth !
I found you .
This was a good town , a good community .
Take me with you , Ruth .
Take me , please .
You can 't join us , Daddy .
But you can help us live .
- l don 't want your blood . - But we want your flesh .
No , no .
Ruth .
We can stop these things .
If we burn them out , they 'll have nowhere to hide .
A couple people looking in the obvious places could do well .
Maybe we 'll get lucky , find some help along the way .
They say fire purifies .
That should count for something .
Mears .
Ben Mears ! Damn you to hell !
Damn you to hell !
Purify .
Oh , man , that 's quite a story .
So the boy lived .
Did he come to Detroit with you ?
Ben ?
Ben !
I got him , Ben. lt 's done .
It 's finished now .
We won . You can rest easy . We won .
Hunting season 's over ?
I don 't believe you .
I can 't .
God bless .
- What 's going on with this guy ? - Bring his chart down .
- Call anesthesia , stat . He needs to be tubed . - Bed down .
Pillows out .
And now i am comforted by thoughts of the town .
i see autumn hills . i pedal my favorite bike down Main Street .
They say you can never go home again , but i did .
i came back to my town .
And in the dark , the town is yours , and you are the town 's .
And together , you sleep like the dead , like the very stones in the old north field .
All clear .
[ english ]